licor.com 2016-04-21

# Privacy and Safe Harbor Information from LI-COR Biosciences.

## Privacy Policy 

LI-COR, INC. complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. LI-COR, INC. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view LI-COR's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

LI-COR collects information from visitors to our website that is voluntarily provided by the user.  
Some downloads request a name and email address so that LI-COR can provide updated information should it become available.  
Individuals asking specific questions through our e-mail response page are asked to provide information so that we can contact them with the information they request.  
LI-COR will not share or sell personal information to any third party.  
If you wish to change or remove your contact information from our database, please send an email to [privacy@licor.com](mailto:privacy@licor.com) or mail your request to:

Director of Marketing Communications   
LI-COR Biosciences  
4647 Superior Street   
Lincoln, NE 68504  
Our Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time. Please review this link regularly for any changes.  
This policy is effective as of June 30, 2004. 

## EU - US Data Privacy Safe Harbor Policy

LI-COR, Inc., and its subsidiaries, respect the privacy of their employees and are committed to protecting employee data maintained by the company. Due to the global nature of LI-COR's business, transfers of employee Personal Data, defined below, across national boundaries may occur. As a result, LI-COR, Inc. ("LI-COR") have adopted this Safe Harbor Data Privacy Policy ("the Privacy Policy") and adhere to the Safe Harbor Principles published by the U.S. Department of Commerce, in agreement with the European Commission, with respect to employee Personal Data transferred from the European Union to the United States of America regarding LI-COR employees employed within the European Union ("EU Based Employees"). 

This Policy applies to all employee Personal Data received by LI-COR in the United States from the European Union ("EU") in any format. For the purpose of this Policy, "Personal Data" or "Personal Information" is employee data about an identified or identifiable EU Based Employee, received by LI-COR in the U.S. from the EU and recorded in any form.

### NOTICE

LI-COR receives employee Personal Information in connection with the management and administration of pre-employment, employment and post-employment matters. LI-COR notifies EU Based Employees about the purposes for which their Personal Information is collected and used. LI-COR will use the information for business operations, employee development, administration and planning, or when required in the course of judicial or administrative proceedings, subject to all nondisclosure safeguards available. Below are listed the general categories of third parties with whom LI-COR may share this Personal Information. Notice to EU Based Employees will be provided before LI-COR uses the information for purposes other than for which it was collected, or before it discloses the information to categories of third parties not specified in this policy. 

### CHOICE

LI-COR gives its EU Based Employees the opportunity to opt out from allowing LI-COR to disclose their Personal Information to a third party or to use it for a purpose incompatible with the purpose for which it was originally collected or authorized. To exercise this opt out, an EU Based Employee should contact the European Managing Director. 

With respect to sensitive data (for example, political or religious beliefs, union membership, health matters), LI-COR will not share such information unless specifically authorized by the individual EU Based Employee.

### TRANSFER TO THIRD PARTIES

LI-COR may share employee data with third parties that provide certain services to LI-COR, including but not limited to outside accountants and lawyers, consultants and service providers. Prior to transferring Personal Data within the LI-COR Group, LI-COR will ensure that the protection and transfer of such Personal Data complies with the Safe Harbor Principles. 

LI-COR may transfer Personal Data to a third party acting as an agent for LI-COR by having the third party enter into an agreement with LI-COR in which the third party promises to provide the same level of protection as required by the Safe Harbor Principles. If the third party agent does not comply with its privacy obligations, LI-COR will take commercially reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure of Personal Data.

### SECURITY

LI-COR takes reasonable measures to protect Personal Information from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. These measures include password protection for online information systems and restricted access to Personal Data processed by the Talent Operations Department. 

### DATA INTEGRITY

LI-COR does not process Personal Information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by the individual. LI-COR will take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is relevant for its intended use, accurate, complete and current. 

### ACCESS

Upon request, LI-COR will provide EU Based Employees with reasonable access to Personal Information that it holds about them and will take reasonable steps to permit the employees to correct, amend, or delete any Personal Information which is inaccurate or incomplete. 

An EU Based Employee who wants to have access to his or her Personal Information should provide a written request to the European Managing Director.

### ENFORCEMENT

Annual internal compliance reviews of the Privacy Policy will take place as part of the certification process with the U.S. Department of Commerce. 

If a complaint regarding LI-COR's use of Personal Information is raised by an EU Based Employee, LI-COR will investigate and try to resolve any dispute. If the dispute cannot be resolved, LI-COR will participate in the dispute resolution procedures of the panel established by the European Data Protection Authorities.

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of Personal Information should be directed to the office of the LI-COR's Chief Compliance Officer indicated below. 

### EMAIL

By opting in, you are agreeing to receive e-mails regarding new products and upgrades, webinars and publications, grants and training opportunities, promotions and discounts, and newsletters. You may update your preferences at any time [here](http://infoenv.licor.com/UnsubscribePage.html) or by following the links in such messages to unsubscribe.

By downloading or installing LI-COR software, you are consenting to receive further information by e-mail regarding the software, including upgrades, modifications, or service notices. You may opt out of such contact by contacting LI-COR [here](http://infoenv.licor.com/UnsubscribePage.html) or by following the links in such messages to unsubscribe.

**Contact Information:**  
Daniel E. Hile  
LI-COR Chief Compliance Officer  
4647 Superior Street  
Lincoln, NE 68504  
USA  
Facsimile: +1 402 467 0860  

### AMENDMENT

The LI-COR Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time in compliance with the requirements of the Safe Harbor Principles. Appropriate notice will be given concerning such amendments.
